Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society Collection 1984.0010
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society Collection
undated, 1768-1977
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1984.0010
24.2 Linear Feet
This collection contains the archive of the Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society. Built on a diverse collection of documents, photographs and artifacts, the collection showcases the history of Hampton from the nineteenth century through early twentieth century.
Location of Copies or Alternate Formats
Digital reproductions of materials in this collection may also be found in the Archives & Special Collections digital repository.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by broad category determined by format or subject.
History
Founded in 1968, the Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society is located at the Burnham-Hibbard House. In 1984, Archives & Special Collections received the Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society's collections on deposit.
Custodial History
With the exception of the records of the Hampton Antiquarian & Historical Society (Series IV), the materials in the collection were donated over time to the HA&HS located in Hampton, CT, as part of the organization's ongoing mission to document the history of Hampton and its environs.
Scope and Content
This broad collection dates from the early nineteenth to the early twentieth century. Featuring Administrative records, awards, books, clippings, correspondence, ephemera, financial records, interviews, legal documents, manuscripts, military records, oral histories, photographs, postcards, posters, publications, realia, and scrapbooks, the collection offers a wide range of sources relevant to the history of Hampton.
Separated materials
The following titles associated with this collection have been cataloged: Hampton Gazette Dodd Periodicals Plan of Development Dodd C 11630
Postcards; Photographs; Publications (documents); Correspondence; Administrative records; Legal documents; Clippings (information artifacts)
- Series I: Account books, Day books and Ledgers, undated, 1795-1950
  - Account book, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Account book, 1826-1831 (Volume 10)
  - Bills and receipts, George Tiffany & Son, Allen Jewett, 1886-1887; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:75 (Box 5, Folder 75, Box 5:75)
  - Burnett, John B., Dr. ledger, 1843-1868 (Volume 20)
  - Button, Charles store ledger, 1831 (Volume 21)
  - Clark, Jonathan ledger, 1829-1857 (Volume 16)
  - Clark, William Day book, 1828 Feb 24 - 1833 March 21 (Volume 18)
  - Clark, William store Day book, 1828 March 7 - 1829 January 19 (Volume 23)
  - [Clark, William ?] store Day book, 1829 (Volume 24)
  - [Clark, William ?] store Day book, 1829 December - 1830 December (Volume 22)
  - Contra Bros. ledger, 1830-1834; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:76 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    Ledgers (account books); Account books; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Contra Co. ledger, 1829-1833 (Volume 15)
  - Darrow ledger, undated (Volume 13)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Volume has little content aside from a brief genealogy of Mr. Darrow, a tin peddlar.]
  - Fox, Joel, account, 1852; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:78 (Box 5:78)
    Financial Records; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society; Fox, Joel
  - Fuller, Elisha Account book, 1833-1854 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - G. & H. Brown, Agent, [Collinsville, CT] Day book, 1872-1873 (Volume 19)
  - Hampton Day book, 1837 April - 1838 March (Volume 25)
  - Index [possibly part of William Clark Day book], undated; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:77 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    indexes (reference sources); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Index to ledger, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:79 (Box 5, Folder 79, Box 5:79)
  - Kimball Kennedy and Co. Day book, 1838-1848 (Volume 12)
  - Manle[?], Clark S. Blotter No. 3, 1838 (Volume 17)
  - Pearl, Arthur, Sr. Account Book, 1900-1950 (Volume 4)
  - [Pearl, Arthur, Sr.] Account Book, 1913-1938 (Volume 3)
  - Phillips Grain Company Day book, 1908 August - 1909 March 24 (Volume 5)
  - Phillips Grain Company Day book, 1909 March 24 - September 7 (Volume 6)
  - Phillips Grain Company Day book, 1909 September 7 - 1910 March 11 (Volume 7)
  - Phillips Grain Company Day book, 1910 September 1 - 1911 February 16 (Volume 8)
  - Phillips Grain Company Day book, 1910 March - October 1 (Volume 9)
  - Phillips Grain Company Ledger, 1896-1900 (Volume 2)
  - Phillips Grain Company Ledger, 1910-1913 (Volume 1)
  - Phillips Grain Company Ledger, 1911-1920, 1928 (Volume 11)
  - Receipts (fragments), circa 1800-1850; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:80 (Box-folder 5:80)
    receipts (financial records); Financial Records; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Receipts and accounts (fragments), circa 1795-1900; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:81 (Box 5:81)
    receipts (financial records); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Receipts and accounts (fragments), 1811-1906; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:82 (Box 5:82)
    Financial Records; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Receipts and accounts (fragments), 1822-1881; 1984-0010/SeriesI/Box5:83 (Box 5:83, Box 5, Folder 83)
- Series II: Photographs, Postcards, undated, 1888-1966
  - Connecticut Tercentenary Postcards (12), 1935; 1984-0010/SeriesII/Box4:72 (Box 4:72, Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Postcards Connecticut), undated, 1906-1966; 1984-0010/SeriesII/Box4:69 (Box-folder 4:69)
    Connecticut (state); Postcards; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Photographs, undated, 1888-1931; 1984-0010/SeriesII/Box4:68 (Box 4:68)
  - Printed images, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesII/Box4:70 (Box 4:70)
    images (object genre); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Calling cards, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesII/Box4:71 (Box 4:71, Box 4, Folder 71)
    visiting cards; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
- Series III: Hampton, CT, undated, 1778-1977
  - Administrative records
    - Town meeting resolves, 1809; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:84 (Box 5:84, Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Bennet, Lucy, verses, 1797; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:85 (Box 5:85, Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Boston, Hartford and Erie Railroad, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Broadside, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cleveland House, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1935, 1969-1973; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box4:73 (Box-folder 4:73)
    Clippings (information artifacts); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Constitutional oak, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1790, 1813; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:86 (Box 5:86, Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence, 1838-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Crossways in the Hills, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dorons, Henry L., State of Connecticut sympathy certificate, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - E. S. Moseley, Elastic Pin, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Election materials
    These files document the legal electors in the Town of Hampton as well as election rolls, 1844, 1874-1905.
    - Information, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - undated (Box 13, Folder 237)
    - 1844 (Box 13, Folder 238)
    - 1874-1875 (Box 13, Folder 239)
    - 1876-1877 (Box 13, Folder 240)
    - 1878-1879 (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - 1880-1883 (Box 13, Folder 242)
    - 1884-1886 (Box 13, Folder 243)
    - 1887-1889 (Box 13, Folder 244)
    - 1890-1892 (Box 13, Folder 245)
    - 1893-1894 (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - 1894 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1895-1897 (Box 13, Folder 247)
    - 1898-1899 (Box 13, Folder 248)
    - 1900-1902 (Box 13, Folder 249)
    - 1903-1905 (Box 13, Folder 250)
    - 1908 (Box 13, Folder 251)
    - 1911 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Financial records, 1809, 1818
    - Canada Society, Tax abatement list, 1778; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:87 (Box 5:87, Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Day labor record, 1796; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:88 (Box 5:88, Box 5, Folder 88)
    - List Book, 1809; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:89 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Road Construction, 1826-1847; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:90 (Box 5:90, Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Road Construction, 1787-1835; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:91 (Box 5, Folder 91, Bin 5:91)
    - Town finances, 1809, 1818, 1909; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:92 (Box 5, Folder 92, Box 5:92, Box 9)
    - Subseries A: Recipts and invoices, undated, 1804-1925; 1898-1920
      This subseries contains receipts and invoices for services and goods provided to the Town of Hampton from 1804 through 1925. The materials document in detail the individuals and local businesses that provided services (snow removal, school children transportation, sign creation, labor on state highway, support of paupers and mentally ill) as well as debts incurred by the Town and interaction with the State of Connecticut financial offices. Taken together the materials in this subseries present a detail view of a small, New England town from the late 19th century into the early 20th century.
      - undated (Box 13, Folder 211, Box 10, Folder 133, Folder 134)
      - 1804 (Box 10, Folder 135)
      - 1855 (Box 10, Folder 136)
      - 1861 (Box 10, Folder 137)
      - 1862 (Box 10, Folder 138)
      - 1863 (Box 13, Folder 212, Box 10, Folder 139)
      - 1864 (Box 13, Folder 213, Box 10, Folder 140)
      - 1865 (Box 13, Folder 214, Box 10, Folder 141)
      - 1869 (Box 10, Folder 142)
      - 1889 (Box 10, Folder 143)
      - 1896 (Box 10, Folder 144)
      - 1897 (Box 10, Folder 145, Box 13, Folder 215)
      - 1898 (Box 10, Folder 146, Folder 147, Box 13, Folder 216)
      - 1899 (Box 13, Folder 217, Box 10, Folder 148, Folder 149)
      - 1900 (Box 10, Folder 150)
      - 1901 (Box 10, Folder 151, Box 13, Folder 218)
      - 1902 (Box 10, Folder 152, Box 13, Folder 219)
      - 1903 (Box 10, Folder 153, Folder 154, Box 13, Folder 220)
      - 1904 (Box 10, Folder 155, Box 13, Folder 221)
      - 1905 (Box 10, Folder 157, Folder 156, Box 13, Folder 222)
      - 1906 (Box 10, Folder 159, Folder 158, Box 13, Folder 223)
      - 1907 (Box 10, Folder 161, Folder 160, Box 13, Folder 224)
      - 1908 (Box 11, Folder 163, Folder 162, Box 13, Folder 225)
      - 1909 (Box 13, Folder 226, Box 11, Folder 165, Folder 164)
      - 1910 (Box 13, Folder 227, Box 11, Folder 166)
      - 1911 (Box 13, Folder 228, Box 11, Folder 167, Folder 168)
      - 1912 (Box 13, Folder 229, Box 11, Folder 169)
      - 1913 (Box 13, Folder 230, Box 11, Folder 171, Folder 170)
      - 1914 (Box 13, Folder 231, Box 11, Folder 172, Folder 173)
      - 1915 (Box 11, Folder 174, Folder 175)
      - 1916 (Box 12, Folder 176, Box 13, Folder 232, Folder 177)
      - 1917 (Box 13, Folder 233, Box 12, Folder 178, Folder 179)
      - 1918 (Box 12, Folder 180, Folder 181, Box 13, Folder 234)
      - 1919 (Box 13, Folder 235, Box 12, Folder 182)
      - 1920 (Box 12, Folder 184, Box 13, Folder 236, Folder 183)
      - 1924 (Box 12, Folder 185)
      - 1925 (Box 12, Folder 186)
  - Fragments, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesII/Box4:74 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Documents (Object genre); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - The Frogs in Windham, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:93 (Box 5:93, Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Fuller, Daniel background research, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fuller, Daniel Common Place book (photocopy), 1806-1807 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gill, Ellen Matilda, 1836-1893 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Goodwin's Pine Acres, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hammond, George A., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hammond, George R., certificate of membership in Windham County Agricultural Society, 1857 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Hampton and the Fullers,", 1936; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:94 (Box 5:94, Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Hampton Community Players, undated, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hampton Congregational Church, 1923-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hammond Dairy, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - House plan, materials and estimate, 1848; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:95 (Box 5, Folder 95, Box 5:95)
  - Hovey Paper, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Is offensive or defensive war justified?, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Jewett Family Record, 1799-1844; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:96 (Box 5:96, Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Legal documents
    - Contracts, 1794-1837; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:97 (Box 5:97, Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Deeds, [1774], 1780-1786; 1780-1786; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:98 (Box 5, Folder 98, Box 5:98)
    - Deeds, 1792-1799; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:99 (Box 5, Folder 99, Box 5:99)
    - Deeds, 1800-1809; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:100 (Box 5:100, Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Deeds, 1810-1819; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:101 (Box 5:101, Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Deeds, 1820-1829; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:102 (Bin 5:102, Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Deeds, 1830-1839; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:103 (Box 5:103, Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Deeds, 1830s; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:104 (Box 5:104, Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Deeds, 1840-1849; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:105 (Box 5:105, Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Deeds, 1850-; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:106 (Box 5:106, Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Lien, 1870 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Probate and court records, 1776, 1823, 1830, 1852, 1889; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box5:107 (Box 5, Folder 107, Box 5:107)
    - Petition to Legislature, 1787 September 21; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:108 (Box 6:108, Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Liberty Pole, Clarks Corners, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Little River Grange, undated, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Maps, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Maps, 1934; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:109 (Box 6:109, Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Meditations on Death and the Grave, 1796 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Memorial Public Library, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Military records
    - Commission signed by Trumbull, Jonathan, 1798; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:110 (Box 6:110, Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Discharge documents, 1863; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:111 (Box 6, Folder 111, Box 6:111)
    - Disability claim, [18]91; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:112 (Box 6:112, Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Pension claim, Sharp, Reuben, 1818; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:113 (Box 6, Folder 113, Box 6:113)
    - Soule, George (Rev.), 1861-1862; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:114 (Box 6:114, Box 6, Folder 114)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, 1908 January 9; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:115 (Box 6:115, Box 6, Folder 115)
  - North Cemetery, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Old Hampton Houses, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Old Home in New England, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Pearl, Patrick H., 1845-1983; 1845-1850 (Box 9, Folder 28, Box 2)
  - Pearl, Phillip, 1847 (Box 9, Folder 29, Box 2)
  - Pearl, Timothy, 1773 (Box 9, Folder 30, Box 2)
  - Pearl, Timothy, Will (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Remnants, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - School records
    - Center School, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - District reports, 1830-1858; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:116 (Box 6:116, Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Publications, 1854, 1859; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:117 (Box 6, Folder 117, Box 6:117)
    - Petition for districts, 1789; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:118 (Box 6, Folder 118, Box 6:118)
    - Record of attendance, 1886; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:119 (Box 6, Folder 119, Box 6:119)
    - Goshen district record book, 1798-1831; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:120 (Box 120, Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Goshen district record book, 1845-1847; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:121 (Box 6:121, Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Goshen district record book, 1858-1909; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:122 (Box 6:122, Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Goshen School register, 1859-1864; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:123 (Box 6, Folder 123, Box 6:123)
    - Goshen School register, 1867-1869; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:124 (Box 6:124, Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Hampton Kindergarten Cooperative
      - Bylaws, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - History and meeting minutes, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Meeting Minutes (Secretary's book), 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - North Bigelow School register, 1866-1871; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box6:125 (Box 6, Folder 125, Box 6:125)
    - School Society record and treasury, 1796-1869 (Volume 14)
    - Schools-at-War program, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Seven Years Along Connecticut Highways, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sewing kit, undated (Box 8)
  - Some Yesterdays of the Homes and the community of Hampton Hill, 1924 Augut (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - State Representatives, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Summertimes, 1938; 1984-0010/SeriesIII/Box7:126 (Box 7, Folder 126, Box 7:126)
  - Vital Statistics, undated, 1876-1897
    - Birth, Marriage and Death
      - undated (Box 12, Folder 187)
      - 1876 (Box 12, Folder 188)
      - 1877 (Box 12, Folder 189)
      - 1878 (Box 12, Folder 190)
      - 1879 (Box 12, Folder 191)
      - 1880 (Box 12, Folder 192)
      - 1881 (Box 12, Folder 193)
      - 1882 (Box 12, Folder 194)
      - 1883 (Box 12, Folder 195)
      - 1884 (Box 12, Folder 196)
      - 1885 (Box 12, Folder 197)
      - 1886 (Box 12, Folder 198)
      - 1887 (Box 12, Folder 199)
      - 1888 (Box 12, Folder 200)
      - 1889 (Box 12, Folder 201)
      - 1890 (Box 12, Folder 202)
      - 1891 (Box 12, Folder 203)
      - 1892 (Box 12, Folder 204)
      - 1893 (Box 12, Folder 205)
      - 1894 (Box 12, Folder 206)
      - 1895 (Box 12, Folder 207)
      - 1896 (Box 12, Folder 208)
      - 1897 (Box 12, Folder 209)
  - World War II ration books, undated, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Series IV: Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society, undated
  - By-Laws, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesIV/Box3:43 (Box 3, Folder 43, Box 3:43)
- Series V: Community, 1825-1976
  - Abington, Connecticut, 1901; 1984-0010/SeriesV/Box3:44 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    Connecticut (state); Abington (inhabited place); Documents (Object genre); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Clapp-Martin marriage certificate, 1867; 1984-0010/SeriesV/Box3:45 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    marriage certificates; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Pomfret [Abington?], Tax list, 1807; 1984-0010/SeriesV/Box3:46 (Box 3:46)
    Tax assessment; Tax collection; Connecticut (state); Pomfret (inhabited place); Abington (inhabited place); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Sharpe family of Abington, CT, 1825-1976; 1984-0010/SeriesV/Box7:127 (Box 7, Folder 127, Box 7:127)
- Series VI: Mildred Stone Papers, undated, 1914-1918; 1984-0010/SeriesVII/Box4:
  - Stone correspondence, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:47; Stone, Mildred L. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    Correspondence; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Mansfield Hollow School, undated, 1914-1918
    - American History, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:48 (Box 3, Folder 48, Box 3:48)
      American history and government; Schools; Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Arithmetic, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:49 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      Arithmetic; Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Arithmetic, Phonetics, etc., undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:50 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Arithmetic; Phonetics
    - English I, 1918; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:51 (Box 3:51)
      English language; Schools; Connecticut (state); Mansfield Hollow; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - English History II, 1914; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:52; Stone, Mildred L. (Box 3, Folder 52)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); United Kingdom (nation); Schools; History--Study and teaching; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Geography, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:53 (Box 3:53)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Geography; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Geography Facts, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:54 (Box 3:54)
    - Grade I Leaflet devices, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:55 (Box 3:55, Box 3, Folder 55)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - History, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:56 (Box 3:56, Box 3, Folder 56)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; History--Study and teaching; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - History Outline, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:57 (Box 3:57)
      History--Study and teaching; Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - History Stories, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:58 (Box 3, Folder 58, Box 3:58)
    - Language, 1915; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:59; Stone, Mildred L. (Box 3, Folder 59, Box-folder 3:59)
      Language arts (Elementary); Schools; Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Language forms, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:60; Stone, Mildred L. (Box-folder 3:60)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Language arts (Elementary); Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Mansfield Hollow School, 1916; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box3:61 (Box 3:61, Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Model School, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box4:62 (Box-folder 4:62, Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Pictures, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box4:63 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Poems, Plays and Games, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box4:64 (Box 4, Folder 64, Box 4:64)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Poetry; Children's plays; Games; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Scrapbook (clippings), undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box4:65 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      Scrapbooks; Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
    - Songs, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVI/Box4:66; Stone, Mildred L. (Box 4, Folder 66)
      Mansfield Hollow; Connecticut (state); Schools; Children's songs; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society; Stone, Mildred L.
- Series VII: Chauncey Cleveland Papers, undated, 1809-1889
  - Cleveland, Chauncey, undated; 1984-0010/SeriesVII/Box4:67 (Box 4, Folder 67, Box 4:67)
    Documents (Object genre); Cleveland, Chauncey F. (Chauncey Fitch), 1799-1887; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society
  - Correspondence [notes about], 1830-1839; 1984-0010/SeriesVII/Box7:128 (Box 7, Folder 128, Box 7:128)
  - Correspondence, 1840-1849; 1984-0010/SeriesVII/Box7:129 (Box 7, Folder 129, Box 7:129)
  - Correspondence, 1860-1889; 1984-0010/SeriesVII/Box7:130 (Box 7:130, Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Deeds, 1832; 1984-0010/SeriesVII/Box7:131 (Box 7, Folder 131, Box 7:131)
  - Legal and financial records, 1809-1860; 1984-0010/SeriesVII/Box7:132 (Box 7, Folder 132, Box 7:132)
    Legal documents; Financial Records; Hampton Antiquarian and Historical Society